Vilnius, Lithuania hello@aleksim.com +370 673 46 095

aleksim.com Linkedin Github

Aleksandr Simonov

Hello, I'm Aleks.

A highly motivated and talented Front-end Developer with a solid foundation in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, and a demonstrated ability to learn and apply new technologies quickly. I specialize in creating responsive web applications using React and Bootstrap frameworks, and have a keen eye for design and user experience.

Core Technical Skills

- HTML/CSS
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- · React.js
 - Next.js (beginner)
 - TypeScript (beginner)
- WordPress
 - WooCommerce
- SQL
- Rest APi
- · SEO (basics)
- · UI/UX (basics)

Soft Skills

- · Critical Thinking
- Effective Communication
- · Stress Management
- Teamwork
- Management

Languages

- English (Proficient)
- · Lithuanian (Native)
- Russian (Proficient)
- · Polish (Basics)

Employment History

Front End Developer for GetThat.Design

Aug 2023 → Present

As a Front-End Developer at a digital design studio GetThat.Design, I learned how to turn creative, intricate designs on Figma into functional and responsive websites. During this time I have sharpened my technical skills in web development and got a better understanding of how to create user-friendly interfaces.

Front End Developer for Juvelyrikos Oaze

Jun 2023 → Nov 2023

I led the development of their business website using React. I used different components to make the design dynamic and responsive and aimed to follow only the best practices in front-end development. The end result - a landing page that fulfilled both aesthetic and functional goals, together demonstrating my capacity for innovative and efficient project execution.

Front End Developer for Mik.lt

Jul 2023 → Feb 2024

For Mik.lt, took the challenge of modernizing a decade-old websites by implementing responsive code, ensuring consisten design across all mobile devices. This task required me to take a deep dive into existing inadequate code structures and introduce more modern front-end development practices.

Other Professional Experience

Co-chef for "Ryžių Jūra"

Nov 2022 → Apr 2023

Contributed significantly to the development of culinary and operational processes. Was responsible for curating half of the restaurant's menu, with a special focus on innovative sushi selection, streamlining kitchen operations, and conducting extensive training for the staff.

Assisting director for "Wasabi Sushi"

May 2020 → Sept 2022

As Assistant Director at Wasabi Sushi my responsibilities consisted of overseeing daily kitchen operations, managing staff, and quality control to meet restaurant's particularly high standards. I succeded in balancing the operational management with the commitment to excellence in food preparation and customer service.

Education

Vilnius Coding School

Sept 2022 → Nov 2022

I have completed a month-long front-end development bootcamp at Vilnius Coding School. This intensive program emphasized hands-on learning in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React, equipping me with the practical knowledge and fundamental technical expertise required to jumpstart in the fast-paced world of web development.

Bachelor of History, Vilnius University

Sept 2012 → Mar 2016

Pursued Bachelor-level History studies at Vilnius University, where I engaged deeply with historical research, critical analysis, and different theoretical perspectives. During this time I advanced my analytical skills, ability to assess diverse information sources critically and substantially improved my written and oral communication abilities. Although I did not complete my studies, the rigorous academic environment contributed significantly to my personal and professional development.